To boil water, we heat it.
我们会加热水来把它烧开
We use ... FIRE.
我们用火来加热
But can we boil water with ice?
但我们能用冰使水沸腾吗
Let's try it.
让我们试试
*Music*
*音乐*
How is it possible?
这怎么可能
We are boiling water with ice.
我们用冰使水沸腾了
To understand this, we must first understand what boiling actually is.
为了理解这一点，我们必须首先知道沸腾到底是什么
Vapor pressure is the tendency of the liquid molecule escape the liquid
蒸气压反映了液体分子离开液体的趋势
When we heat a liquid,
若我们加热一种液体
its vapor pressure increases and (it is? *inaudible *) just at the atmospheric pressure,
它的蒸气压增加 并且（听不清）
that is when the liquid molecules start to escape the liquid rapidly.
这时下液体分子会快速离开液体
And this escape zone is boiling.
这个逃离区域就是沸腾区域
But what if instead of increasing the vapor pressure of the liquid,
但是如果我们不去升高液体的蒸气压
We can somehow bring down the atmospheric pressure to the vapor pressure of the liquid.
我们可以用某些方法把气压降低到液体的蒸气压
To do that, we first isolate a liquid,
为了实现这一点 我们首先分离一些液体
and then we use ice to cool down the air around the liquid
然后我们用冰来降低液体周围空气的温度
and atmospheric pressure in this *** *** ** goes down.
随后这个***中的气压降低
And when it matches the vapor pressure of the liquid,
当气压和液体的蒸气压相同时
The liquid starts to boiling
液体就开始沸腾
That's how to boil water using ice.
这就是用冰使水沸腾的方法
******
干杯(?)